Sync By: Luis-Subs
Improved By: Fidel33
JOY: Do you ever look
at someone and wonder...
"What is going on
inside their head?"
Well, I know.
Well, I know Riley's head.
(BABY COOING)
Hmm?
(BABY COOING HAPPILY)
JOY: And there she was...
Hello. Riley.
Oh, look at you.
Aren't you a
little bundle of joy?
(BELL DINGS)
Aren't you a little
bundle of joy?
Whoa.
(RILEY COOING)
JOY: It was amazing.
Just Riley and me. Forever.
(RILEY CRYING)
JOY: Err, for 33 seconds?
I'm Sadness.
Oh, hello.
I... I'm Joy. So...
Can I just... If you could...
I just want to fix that. Thanks.
JOY: And that was
just the beginning.
Headquarters only got
more crowded from there.
(LAUGHING)
Very nice. Okay, looks like
you got this. Very good.
FEAR: Whoa, sharp turn!
No! Look out! No!
JOY: That's Fear.
He's really good
at keeping Riley safe.
FEAR: Easy, easy. Ah!
(EXCLAIMS) Oh,
we're good. We're good.
- Whew! Good job.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- And we're back!
- (RILEY LAUGHING)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- Oh!
Here we go. All right, open.
- Hmm. This looks new.
- You think it's safe?
- What is it?
- Aah.
Okay, caution.
There is a dangerous smell, people.
- Hold on. What is that?
- JOY: This is Disgust.
She basically keeps Riley
from being poisoned.
Physically and socially
That is not brightly colored
or shaped like a dinosaur.
Hold on, guys.
It's broccoli!
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Yucky!
Well, I just saved our lives.
- BOTH: Whew!
- Yeah. You're welcome.
Riley, if you don't eat your dinner,
you're not gonna get any dessert.
Wait. Did he just say
we couldn't have dessert?
JOY: That's Anger.
He cares very deeply
about things being fair.
So that's how you
want to play it, old man?
No dessert? Oh, sure,
we'll eat our dinner!
Right after you eat this!
(YELLING)
Riley, Riley,
here comes an airplane!
(MIMICS ENGINE HUMMING)
Oh, airplane.
We got an airplane, everybody.
- ALL: Oh!
- Airplane.
JOY: And you've met Sadness.
She... Well, she...
(CRYING)
JOY: I'm not actually sure
what she does.
And I've checked,
there's no place for her to go, so...
She's good,
we're good. It's all great!
Anyway, these are Riley's memories
and they're mostly happy,
you'll notice. Not to brag.
- MEG: Whoo-hoo!
- (RILEY LAUGHING)
Whoo-hoo!
JOY: But the really
important ones are over here.
I don't want to get too technical,
but these are called Core Memories.
Each one came from
a super important time in Riley's life.
Uh, like when she first scored a goal.
Oh, that was so amazing!
Hey! Would you look at that? Very nice!
- We got a future center here!
- Nice job.
(ALL CHEERING)
JOY: And each Core Memory
powers a different aspect
of Riley's personality.
Like Hockey Island.
Goofball Island
is my personal favorite.
Ah, come back here,
you little monkey!
DAD: (LAUGHING) Oh, you're silly.
JOY: Yep, Goofball is the best.
Friendship Island
is pretty good too.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
JOY: Oh, I love Honesty Island.
And that's the truth!
And of course,
Family Island is amazing.
(INDISTINCT)
JOY: The point is,
the Islands of Personality
are what make Riley... Riley!
Look out, mermaid! (SPLASHING)
(GIGGLING)
(BUBBLING)
Lava! Whee!
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong! ♪
- Hey! Very nice!
- Where'd you learn that?
(SLURPING) Ahhh!
- Brain freeze!
- (ALL SCREAMING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
- Yeah!
Good night, kiddo.
Good night, Dad.
And... we're out!
JOY: That's what I'm talking about!
Whoo! Another perfect day!
Nice job, everybody!
Let's get those memories
down to Long Term.
All right, we did not die today!
I call that an unqualified success.
JOY: And that's it. We love our girl.
She's got great friends
and a great house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all, Riley's 11 now.
What could happen?
- What...
- ALL: Aah!
- (JOY GASPS)
- (ALL EXCLAIM)
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTING)
Okay, not what I had in mind.
(ALL SCREAMS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
JOY: Hey, look!
The Golden Gate Bridge!
Isn't that great?
It's not made out of
solid gold like we thought,
which is kind of
a disappointment, but still...
FEAR: I sure am glad you told me
earthquakes are a myth, Joy.
Otherwise I'd be terrified right now!
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, yeah...
WOMAN: Are you kidding?
Get out of the street!
- (CARS HONKING)
- MAN: Oh, for Pete's sake! Move it!
- These are my kind of people.
- (CARS HONKING)
DAD: All right,
just a few more blocks.
We're almost to our new house!
Step on it, Daddy!
Why don't we just live
in this smelly car?
We've already been in it forever.
Which, actually, was really lucky,
because that gave us
plenty of time to think about
what our new house
is going to look like!
What! Let's review
the top five daydreams.
- Ooh! That looks safe!
- SADNESS: That one's nice.
Oh, this will be great for Riley!
JOY: Oh, no, no, no, no, this one!
DISGUST: Oh, Joy, for the last time,
she cannot live in a cookie.
ANGER: That's the one!
It comes with a dragon.
JOY: Now we're getting close,
I can feel it.
Here it is, here's our new house.
And...
Maybe it's nice on the inside.
(DOOR CREAKING)
- ANGER: We're supposed to live here?
- SADNESS: Do we have to?
DISGUST: I'm telling you,
it smells like something died in here.
Can you die from moving?
Guys, you're overreacting.
Nobody is dying...
- A dead mouse!
- (FEAR SCREAMS)
- ANGER: Great. This is just great.
- DISGUST: I'm gonna be sick.
It's the house of the dead!
We're going to get rabies!
- Get off of me!
- (FEAR SCREAMING)
Hey. All through the drive,
Dad talked about
how cool our new room is.
- (FEAR SIGHS)
- Let's go check it out!
- DISGUST: Let's go!
- ANGER: It's gonna be great!
FEAR: Yes, yes, yes.
No, no, no, no, no.
DISGUST: I'm starting
to envy the dead mouse.
ANGER: Get out the rubber ball,
we're in solitary confinement.
Riley can't live here.
- She's right.
- It's the worst.
- FEAR: Really bad.
- DISGUST: It's absolutely the worst.
DISGUST: It's the worst place
I've ever been in my entire life.
Hey, it's nothing
our butterfly curtains couldn't fix.
I read somewhere
that an empty room is an opportunity.
- Where did you read that?
- It doesn't matter.
I read it and it's great.
We'll put the bed there.
JOY: And the desk over there.
FEAR: The hockey lamp goes there.
ANGER: Uh, put the chair there.
JOY: The trophy collection goes there.
FEAR: Stars! I like that!
JOY: Now we're talking!
Let's go get our stuff
from the moving van!
DAD: All right. Goodbye.
Well, guess what?
The moving van
won't be here until Thursday.
- You're kidding.
- Mmm-hmm.
The van is lost?
It is the worst day ever!
DISGUST: That figures. The van is lost.
You said it would be here yesterday!
I know that's what I said.
That's what they told me!
FEAR: Mom and Dad are stressed out!
- ANGER: They're stressed out?
- FEAR: What are we going to do?
- (ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
- I've got a great idea!
Did you even read the contract?
Andersen makes her move.
She's closing in!
Hey! (LAUGHS)
DAD: Oh, no, you're not!
She's lining up for the shot!
DAD: Coming behind you.
- DAD: Watch out! Watch out!
- She shoots and she scores!
- Yeah!
- (ALL CHEERING)
- Come on, Grandma!
- Ha!
"Grandma"?
Uh-oh, she put her hair up,
we're in for it!
Whoo!
- Hey, put me down!
- (DAD LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(BELL DINGS)
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Ah! Sorry.
Hold on. Hold on.
- Hello?
- Wait. Wh...
DAD: You're kidding.
(SIGHS) All right. Stall for me.
I'll be right there.
The investor's supposed
to show up on Thursday,
not today!
- (SIGHS)
- I got to go.
It's okay. We get it.
You're the best. Thanks, hon.
See you, sweetie.
FEAR: Dad just left us.
He doesn't love us anymore.
That's sad.
I should drive, right?
Joy?
What are you doing?
Uh, just give me one second.
Um, you know what I've realized?
Riley hasn't had lunch! Remember?
Hey, I saw a pizza place
down the street.
Maybe we could try that?
Pizza sounds delicious.
- Pizza? That's good.
- Yes! Pizza!
- FEAR: What the heck is that?
- JOY: Who puts broccoli on pizza?
That's it. I'm done.
Congratulations, San Francisco,
you've ruined pizza!
First the Hawaiians
and now you!
What kind of a pizza place
only serves one kind of pizza?
MOM: Must be a
San Francisco thing, huh?
Still, it's not as bad as that soup.
- At that diner in Nebraska.
- Oh, yeah.
The spoon stood up
in the soup by itself!
RILEY: That was disgusting.
JOY: Oh, good. Family is running.
RILEY: Dad's got a steel stomach.
The drive out was pretty fun, huh?
What was your favorite part?
Spitting out the car window!
Definitely not when Dad was singing.
Wearing a seat belt!
Oh! What about the time
with the dinosaur?
- Oh, that's the one.
- Definitely!
DAD: Say cheese!
- Dad! Dad!
- Honey!
- DAD: Now hold still.
- MOM: The car!
Stop! No, no, no! (GRUNTING)
(DAD GROANS)
(LAUGHS) Nice one, Joy.
I liked that time at the dinosaur.
- That was pretty funny.
- (MOM LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Wait. What? What happened?
FEAR: She did something to the memory.
- What did you do?
- I just touched it.
- That shouldn't make it change.
- Change it back, Joy!
- I'm trying.
- You can't change it back?
- No! I guess I can't!
- Good going, Sadness.
Now when Riley thinks
of that moment with Dad,
she's gonna feel sad.
- Bravo.
- I'm sorry, Joy.
I don't really know...
I thought maybe if you...
(STAMMERING)
Joy, we've got a stairway coming up.
Just don't touch any other memories
until we figure out what's going on.
- Okay.
- JOY: All right.
Get ready. This is a monster railing
and we are riding it all the way down!
- Wait, what? What happened?
- (CLATTERING)
- (FEAR AND JOY GASP)
- A Core Memory!
Oh, no!
Sadness, what are you doing?
SADNESS: It looked like one was crooked
so I opened it and then it fell out.
I...
Whoo-hoo!
It's just that...
I wanted to maybe hold one.
- FEAR: Joy!
- Whoa, whoa!
Sadness, you nearly
touched a Core Memory.
And when you touch them,
we can't change them back.
I know. I'm sorry.
Something's wrong with me.
It's like I'm having a breakdown.
You're not having
a breakdown. It's stress.
I keep making mistakes like that.
I'm awful.
- No, you're not.
- And annoying.
(STUTTERING) You know what?
You can't focus on what's going wrong.
There's always a way to
turn things around,
to find the fun.
Yeah. Find the fun.
I don't know how to do that.
Okay. Well,
try to think of something funny.
Um... Oh!
Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies?
Oh. Yeah, that's not...
What about that time with Meg
when Riley laughed so hard
milk came out of her nose?
(LAUGHING)
Yeah. That hurt. It felt like fire.
SADNESS: Ooh, it was awful.
Okay, okay, don't think of that.
Let's try something else.
Uh, what are your favorite things to do?
My favorite?
Um... Well, I like it
when we're outside.
That's good. Like there's
the beach and sunshine.
Oh! Like that time
we buried Dad
in the sand up to his neck.
SADNESS: I was thinking more like rain.
Rain? Rain is my favorite, too!
We can stomp around in puddles.
JOY: You know, there's cool
umbrellas, lightning storms.
SADNESS: More like when
the rain runs down our back
and makes our shoes soggy.
And we get all cold, shivery, and
everything just starts
feeling droopy. (CRYING)
Oh, hey, hey. Hey, easy.
Why are you crying?
It's just like really the opposite
of what we're going for here.
Crying helps me slow down and obsess
over the weight of life's problems.
(JOY SIGHS)
You know what? Let's, uh,
think about something else. (GRUNTS)
How about we read
some mind manuals, huh?
- Sounds fun.
- I've read most of them.
Well, have you read this one?
This seems interesting.
"Long Term Memory Retrieval, Volume 47"?
- No.
- Ooh, a real page-turner!
"Long Term Memory data selection
"via channel subgrouping"?
See? Fun already!
Oh, you lucky dog.
You're reading these cool things.
I got to go work. Life is so unfair.
(SIGHS)
(BELL DINGS)
(GROANS)
DAD: What can we do?
We've only got capital
to last a month, maybe two.
If we can't find investors by then,
we're going to have to lay people off.
Mom! Dad!
Come kiss me good night!
- DAD: I know. I know.
- MOM: Be right there!
DAD: We've got to land this, okay?
Did you hear Dad?
He sounded really upset.
- (VEHICLE PASSING)
- (GASPS)
(RUMBLING)
What was that?
Was it a bear? It's a bear!
There are no bears in San Francisco.
I saw a really hairy guy.
He looked like a bear.
Oh, I'm so jumpy. My nerves are shot.
Ew! I don't want to
hear about your nerves.
I'll tell you what it is.
This move has been a bust.
FEAR: That's what I've been
telling you guys!
There are at least 37 things for
Riley to be scared of right now.
The smell alone is
enough to make her gag.
ANGER: I can't believe
Mom and Dad moved us here!
Look, I get it. You guys have concerns.
But we've been through worse!
Tell you what,
let's make a list of all the things
Riley should be happy about.
Fine. Let's see, this house stinks,
our room stinks.
- Pizza is weird here.
- Our friends are back home.
And all of our stuff
is in the missing van!
Oh, come on. It could be worse.
Yeah, Joy. We could be
lying on the dirty floor. In a bag.
Okay, I admit it, we had a rough start.
But think of all the good things that...
No, Joy. There's
absolutely no reason for Riley
to be happy right now.
Let us handle this.
I say we skip school tomorrow
and lock ourselves in the bedroom.
We have no clean clothes.
I mean, no one should see us.
Yeah, we could cry
until we can't breathe.
We should lock the door
and scream that curse word we know.
- It's a good one!
- Now hold on!
Look, we all have our off days.
- You know...
- Hi, honey.
The Mom bad news train is pulling in.
Toot-toot!
Still no moving van. (SCOFFS)
Now they're saying it won't be here
till Tuesday, can you believe it?
Toot-toot-toot!
- Where's Dad?
- On the phone.
This new venture
is keeping him pretty busy.
I rest my case!
MOM: Oh, your dad's a little stressed,
you know, about getting
his new company up and running.
Now for a few
well-placed withering scowls.
(SIGHS)
I guess all I really
want to say is, thank you.
- Huh?
- MOM: You know,
through all this confusion
you've stayed...
(LAUGHS) Well,
you've stayed our happy girl.
MOM: Your dad's under
a lot of pressure,
but if you and I can keep smiling,
it would be a big help.
We can do that for him. Right?
Whoa.
JOY: Well.
Yeah, sure.
What did we do to deserve you?
- Sweet dreams.
- RILEY: Good night.
Well, you can't argue
with Mom. Happy it is.
Team Happy! Sounds great!
Totally behind you, Joy.
Looks like we're going into REM.
I got Dream Duty, so I'll take care
of sending these to Long Term.
JOY: Great day today, guys!
- Oh, sleep well, Team Happy!
- (ALL TALKING AT ONCE)
All right, what's on tonight,
Dream Production?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Well, this is it. The new place.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(VOICES MOANING)
Come live with me, Riley. (GRUNTS)
Somebody order a broccoli pizza?
- Eat me!
- I'm organic!
(SIGHS) No! Who is in charge
of programming down there?
I know I'm not supposed
to do this, but...
We are not going to
end the day like this.
(RILEY LAUGHING)
Don't you worry.
I'm gonna make sure
that tomorrow is another great day.
I promise.
(RILEY GIGGLES)
(ENERGETIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello! Did I wake you?
- ANGER: Do you have to play that?
- Well, I have to practice.
And I don't think of it as playing
so much as hugging.
Okay, first day of school!
Very, very exciting.
I was up late last night
figuring out a new plan.
- Here it is! Fear.
- (GASPS)
I need a list of all the possible
negative outcomes
on the first day at a new school.
Way ahead of you there. Does anyone
know how to spell "meteor"?
Disgust. Make sure
Riley stands out today.
But also blends in.
When I'm through,
Riley will look so good,
the other kids will
look at their own outfits and barf.
"Joy." "Yes, Joy?"
"You'll be in charge of the console,
"keeping Riley happy all day long.
"And may I add I love
your dress? It's adorable."
"Oh, this old thing?
Thank you so much.
"I love the way it twirls."
- (TRAIN HORN BLOWS)
- Train of Thought! Right on schedule.
(TRAIN HONKS HORN)
Anger. Unload the daydreams.
I ordered extra
in case things get slow in class.
It might come in handy.
If this new school is full of
boring, useless classes.
Which it probably will be.
Oh. Sadness. I have
a super important job just for you.
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm. Follow me.
- What are you doing?
- And there. Perfect!
This is the circle of Sadness.
Your job is to make sure that
all the Sadness stays inside of it.
So you want me to just stand here?
Hey, it's not my place to
tell you how to do your job.
Just make sure that all the Sadness
stays in the circle!
See? You're a pro at this!
Isn't this fun?
- No.
- Atta girl.
All right, everyone, fresh start.
We are gonna have a good day,
which will turn into a good week,
which will turn into a good year,
which turns into a good life!
So, the big day!
New school, new friends, huh?
I know! I'm kind of nervous,
but I'm mostly excited.
How do I look? Do you like my shirt?
MOM: Very cute!
Are you gonna be okay?
You want us to walk with you?
Mom and Dad? With us in public?
No thank you.
Uh... I'm on it!
Nope! I'm fine. Bye, Mom. Bye, Dad.
Have a good day at school, monkey.
(IMITATING MONKEY GRUNTING)
MOM: Have a great day, sweetheart!
GIRL #1: That's crazy. It really is.
GIRL #2: That was so funny.
BOY: Do you know
what basketball game is coming up?
FEAR: Are you sure we want to do this?
- JOY: In we go!
- FEAR: Okay! Going in! Yes!
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
GIRL: Did you see her? Hello!
DISGUST: Okay, we've got
a group of cool girls at two o'clock.
- How do you know?
- Double ears pierced,
infinity scarf.
JOY: Whoa. Is she wearing eye shadow?
- Yeah, we want to be friends with them.
- Let's go talk to them!
Are you kidding?
We're not talking to them.
We want them to like us.
Oh. Yeah. Wait, what?
Almost finished
with the potential disasters.
Worst scenario is either quicksand,
spontaneous combustion,
or getting called on by the teacher.
So as long as none of those happen...
Okay, everybody.
We have a new student in class today.
Are you kidding me? Out of the gate?
This is not happening!
Riley, would you like
to tell us something about yourself?
No! Pretend we can't speak English.
Don't worry. I got this.
Uh... Okay.
My name is Riley Andersen.
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
TEACHER: And how about Minnesota?
Can you tell us something about it?
Well, you certainly
get a lot more snow than we do.
(LAUGHING)
She's hilarious!
Yeah, it gets pretty cold.
The lake freezes over,
and that's when we play hockey.
I'm on a great team.
We're called the Prairie Dogs.
My friend Meg plays forward.
And my dad's the coach.
Pretty much everyone
in my family skates.
It's kind of a family tradition.
We go out on the lake
almost every weekend.
Or we did, till I moved away.
- Hey, what gives?
- Wait, what?
Hey, Sadness! You touched
a memory? We talked about this.
Oh, yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
Get back in your circle.
(SIGHS) What's going on?
- Why won't it eject?
- Get it out of there, Joy.
(SNIFFLING) We used
to play tag and stuff.
Cool kids whispering at three o'clock!
- FEAR: Did you see that look?
- JOY: Oh, no.
They're judging us!
(ALL STRAINING)
JOY: Somebody help me!
Grab that... Everybody put...
But everything's different now.
Since we moved.
(SNIFFLES)
Oh, no! We're crying! At school!
What? Sadness! What are you doing?
Oh, no! Oh, I'm sorry!
JOY: Huh?
FEAR: (GASPS) It's a Core Memory!
But it's blue.
(ALL GASP)
No! Wait! Stop it! No! Ah! No!
Joy, no.
- That's a Core Memory!
- Hey!
- Joy, wait!
- Stop it! Let go!
FEAR: Ah! The Core Memories!
(EXCLAIMS)
(GASPS)
No, no, no, no!
- Whoa!
(FEAR GASPS)
TEACHER: Thank you, Riley.
I know it can be tough
moving to a new place,
but we're happy to have you here.
All right, everyone,
get out your history books
and turn to chapter seven.
Can I say that curse word now?
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
- (SADNESS SCREAMING)
- Ah!
Oh, no! One, two, three. Okay.
I got them. Where are we?
Long Term Memory? Wait...
Goofball Island?
SADNESS: Riley's Islands of Personality.
They're all down!
Oh! This is bad.
We... We can fix this!
We just have to
get back to Headquarters,
plug the Core Memories in,
and Riley will be back to normal.
Riley has no Core Memories.
No Personality Islands and no...
(GASPS)
What? What is it?
You.
You're not in Headquarters.
Without you, Riley can't be happy.
We got to get you back up there.
I'm coming, Riley.
So, as it turns out, the green trash can
is not recycling, it's for greens.
- Like compost. And eggshells.
- Mmm.
And the blue one is recycling.
- MOM: And the black one is trash.
- Riley is acting so weird.
Why is she acting so weird?
What do you expect?
All the Islands are down.
Joy would know what to do.
That's it.
Until she gets back,
we just do what Joy would do!
Great idea. Anger, Fear, Disgust,
how are we supposed to be happy?
MOM: Hey, Riley. I've got good news!
I found a junior hockey league
right here in San Francisco.
And get this: Try-outs are tomorrow
after school. What luck, right?
- Hockey?
- Uh-oh. What do we do?
(STUTTERING) Guys, this is...
You pretend to be Joy.
Won't it be great to be
back out on the ice?
Oh, yeah, that sounds fantastic.
What was that?
That wasn't anything like Joy!
- Uh, because I'm not Joy.
- Yeah, no kidding.
Did you guys pick up on that?
- Mmm-hmm. Something's wrong.
- Totally.
Should we ask her?
Let's probe. But keep it subtle,
so she doesn't notice.
So, how was the first day of school?
She's probing us.
I'm done. You pretend to be Joy.
What? Okay. Um, hmm.
It was fine, I guess. I don't know.
Oh. Very smooth.
That was just like Joy.
Something is definitely going on.
She's never acted like this before.
What should we do?
We're going to
find out what's happening.
But we'll need support.
Signal the husband.
Ahem!
ANNOUNCER: With a nice
pass over to Reeves,
comes across ...and nice!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Uh-oh. She's looking at us.
Uh, what did she say?
What? Oh! Sorry, sir.
No one was listening.
Is it garbage night?
We left the toilet seat up?
What? What is it, woman? What?
Ugh, he's making
that stupid face again.
MOM'S ANGER: I could strangle
him right now.
Signal him again.
Ah! So, Riley, how was school?
- You got to be kidding me!
- Seriously?
For this we gave up
that Brazilian helicopter pilot?
Move! I'll be Joy.
School was great, all right?
Riley. Is everything okay?
Ugh!
Sir, she just rolled her eyes at us.
What is her deal?
All right, make a show of force.
I don't want to have to
put "the foot" down.
No, not the foot!
Riley, I do not like this new attitude.
Oh, I'll show you attitude, old man.
No. No, no, no! Stay happy!
What is your problem?
Just leave me alone!
Sir, reporting high levels of sass!
Take it to DEFCON Two.
You heard that, gentlemen. DEFCON Two.
(ALARMS BLARING)
Listen, young lady,
I don't know where...
...this disrespectful
attitude came from...
You want a piece of this, pops?
Come and get it!
Yeah, well... Well...
Here it comes. Prepare the foot!
Keys to safety position.
Ready to launch
on your command, sir!
(YELLING)
Just shut up!
Fire!
That's it! Go to your room! Now!
Uh!
(RILEY GRUNTING)
The foot is down!
(ALL CHEERING)
Good job, gentlemen.
That could have been a disaster.
Well, that was a disaster.
Come fly with me, gatinha.
(ALL SIGHS)
(RUMBLING)
(JOY SIGHS)
We're going to walk out there? On that?
JOY: It's the quickest way back.
But it's right over the Memory Dump.
If we fall, we'll be forgotten forever.
We have to do this for Riley.
Just follow my footsteps.
- Oh, okay.
- It's not that high.
It's totally fine...
(JOY GRUNTING)
No!
(GRUNTS)
- (KNOCK ON DOOR)
- (DOOR OPENS)
Hey.
So, uh, things got a little
out of hand downstairs.
Do you want to talk about it?
Come on, where's my happy girl?
Monkey. (IMITATING MONKEY GRUNTING)
Oh, he's trying to start up Goofball.
DAD: Come on!
(DAD CONTINUES GRUNTING)
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Ah!
Go back! Run, run, run!
(JOY PANTING)
(GASPS)
(BOTH PANTING)
What...
I get it. You need some alone time.
We'll talk later.
DISGUST: We have a major problem.
FEAR: Oh, Joy, where are you?
SADNESS: We lost Goofball Island.
That means she can lose Friendship
and Hockey and Honesty and Family.
You can fix this, right, Joy?
I, uh... I don't know.
- Oh...
- But we have to try.
Okay, come on.
(MACHINERY POWERING DOWN)
- Riley's gone to sleep.
- Oh...
Which is a good thing.
When you think about it because
nothing else bad
can happen while she's asleep.
We'll be back to Headquarters
before she wakes up.
We'll just go across Friendship Island.
Oh, we'll never make it.
- Oh, no!
- No, no, no!
Don't obsess over
the weight of life's problems.
Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies?
Oh, Sadness,
we don't have time for this.
We'll just have to go around.
Take the scenic route.
SADNESS: Wait, Joy,
you could get lost in there!
Think positive!
SADNESS: Okay. I'm positive
you will get lost in there.
SADNESS: That's Long Term Memory.
An endless warren
of corridors and shelves.
I read about it in the manuals.
The manuals?
The manuals!
- You read the manuals!
- Yeah.
So you know the way
back to Headquarters!
I guess.
Ooh! (CHUCKLES EXCITEDLY)
You are my map!
Let's go! Lead on, my map!
Show me where we're going!
Okay. Only I'm too sad to walk.
Just give me a few... hours.
Ooh!
JOY: Which way? Left?
SADNESS: Right.
No. I mean, go left.
I said left was right. Like "correct."
JOY: Okay.
SADNESS: This actually
feels kind of nice.
Okay, here we go!
We'll be back to Headquarters
before morning.
We can do it! This will be easy!
This is working!
(GROANS)
This is not working.
Are we getting close?
SADNESS: Yeah, just another right.
And... a left and then
another... left and...
Uh, are you sure
you know where we're going?
Because we seem to be
walking away from Headquarters.
Riley's awake.
Ooh! Oh!
(EXCLAIMS NERVOUSLY)
Don't touch. Remember?
If you touch them, they stay sad.
Oh, sorry, I won't. Starting now.
Oh, I can't take much more of this.
FORGETTER BOBBY: Forget them!
Mind workers!
But, Joy, we're almost...
(SIGHS)
Phone numbers.
We don't need all these.
They're in her phone.
- Excuse me, hi.
- Just forget all of that. Please. Forget it!
- I need to find Friendship Island.
- Look at this.
Four years of piano lessons.
FORGETTER BOBBY: Yeah,
it looks pretty faded.
You know what? Save Chopsticks
and Heart and Soul, get rid of the rest.
- Are you...
- US Presidents. What do you think?
Yeah, just keep
Washington, Lincoln and the fat one.
- Forget 'em!
- Hey!
You can't throw those away!
Those are perfectly good memories.
The names of
every "Cutie Pie Princess" doll?
Yes! That is critical information!
JOY: Glitterstorm, Honeypants...
Forget 'em!
Hey! Bring those back!
They're in the dump. Nothing
comes back from the dump.
Yeah. Look, lady, this is our job, okay?
When Riley doesn't care
about a memory, it fades.
- Fades?
- Happens to the best of them.
Yeah, except for this bad boy.
(LAUGHS) This one will never fade.
- MAN: ♪ TripleDent gum ♪
- WOMAN: ♪ Will make you smile ♪
(GASPS) The song
from the gum commercial?
You know, sometimes we send that one
up to Headquarters for no reason.
It just plays in Riley's head
over and over again.
- Like a million times!
- (LAUGHS)
Let's watch it again!
♪ TripleDent gum ♪
Yeah, I know. We all know the song.
Okay. Yeah, real catchy. Okay.
Hey, what do you think? Should we do it?
Yeah!
Okay, here we go!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
♪ TripleDent gum ♪
What the... This again?
(SINGING ALONG)
Wait! Do you know how to
get to Friendship Island?
♪ TripleDent gum ♪
Do you like it there?
Did you feel any earthquakes?
Is the bridge cool?
Yeah, it's good.
What happened with the playoffs?
We won the first game.
Coach says we might actually
go to the finals this year.
Oh, and we've got
this new girl on the team.
She's so cool.
Uh, she did not just say that.
A new girl? Meg has
a new friend already?
- (ANGER GRUMBLING)
- Hey, hey! Stay happy!
We do not want to lose
any more islands here, guys!
MEG: We can pass the puck to each other
without even looking.
It's like mind reading!
You like to read minds, Meg?
I got something
for you to read, right here!
Let's just be calm for one second! Ahhh!
(YELLING)
- MEG: I heard they have parrots...
- I've got to go.
- What?
- I got to go!
Okay, could you just please
tell me which way is...
(BOTH CHATTERING)
- (RUMBLING)
- Oh, no!
Friendship Island! What?
Oh, not Friendship.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, Riley loved that one.
And now it's gone.
Goodbye, friendship.
- (SIGHS)
- Hello, loneliness.
(GRUMBLING)
We'll just have to go the long way.
Yeah. The long, long, long, long way.
SADNESS: I'm ready.
(GROANS) There's got to be a better way.
- (BING BONG HUMMING)
- (GASPS)
BING BONG: Ooh! Look at you!
Huh?
I will take you, but not you.
Oh, who am I kidding? I can't leave you.
- Hello!
- (BING BONG EXCLAIMS)
Wait! Hey! Wait!
(CLATTERING)
Oh, wait! Stop!
(BING BONG PANTING)
- Excuse me.
- Ah!
Uh, I was looking for, um... Diversion!
- JOY: What?
- Ha-ha! So long, sucker!
(CLATTERING)
BING BONG: Ow, I hurt all over.
Wait. I know you.
No, you don't. I get that a lot.
I look like a lot of people.
No, no, no. I do. (GASPS)
Bing Bong! Riley's imaginary friend!
- You really do know me?
- Well, of course!
Riley loved playing with you!
You two are best friends!
Oh! Oh, you would know.
We're trying to get
back to Headquarters.
Headquarters? You guys
are from Headquarters?
Well, yeah. I'm Joy. This is Sadness.
- You're Joy? The Joy?
- JOY: Mmm-hmm.
What the heck are you doing out here?
That's a good question.
You want to answer that, Sadness?
Wow. Without you,
Riley won't ever be happy.
We can't have that.
We got to get you back.
I'll tell you what. Follow me!
Oh, thank you!
It is so great to see you again.
I gotta tell you, I am such
a huge fan of your work.
Do you remember when you
and Riley were in a band?
(LAUGHS) I went to all of your concerts.
BING BONG: Yeah, I blow a mean nose.
JOY: Watching you play tag
was such a treat.
BING BONG: Two-time world champ.
JOY: Oh! And remember your rockets?
BING BONG: Of course!
It runs on song power!
That's right! Your theme song!
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong
Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" ♪
BOTH: ♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
What exactly are you supposed to be?
You know, it's unclear.
I'm mostly cotton candy.
But shape-wise I'm part cat,
part elephant, part dolphin.
Dolphin?
(MIMICS DOLPHIN CLICKING)
You got to remember,
when Riley was three,
animals were all the rage.
The cow goes moo.
The horse goes neigh.
That's all people talked
about back then.
Yeah. Yeah. I guess that's true.
What are you doing out here?
Well, there's not much call
for imaginary friends lately.
So, uh, I, you know, um...
(SIGHS)
Hey, hey. Don't be sad.
Tell you what. When I get
back up to Headquarters,
I'll make sure Riley remembers you.
- You will?
- Of course!
- She'd love that.
- (LAUGHING)
This is the greatest day of my life!
Ha, cha, cha, cha, cha. Ow!
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Oh, are you okay?
Hey, what's going on?
I cry candy.
Try the caramel. It's delicious.
Ooh. Whoa!
Ooh, here, use this.
- Thanks!
- Whoa, hold on, wait a second.
(GRUNTING)
It always gets stuck at the bottom.
- (TRUMPET BLOWS)
- (CAT SCREECHING)
Here. What? It's imaginary.
Thanks. This will make it a lot easier
to walk back to Headquarters.
Walk? We're not walking.
We're taking the Train of Thought!
(HORN BLARING)
JOY: The train, of course!
That is so much faster!
But how do we catch it?
Well, it kind of goes
all over the place,
but there is a station
in Imagination Land.
I know a shortcut.
Come on, this way!
JOY: Oh, I am so glad we ran into you!
The station is right
through here. After you.
- Joy.
- What?
I read about this place
in the manual. We shouldn't go in there.
Bing Bong says
it's the quickest way to Headquarters.
No, but, Joy, this is abstract thought.
What are you talking about?
I go in here all the time.
It's a shortcut, you see?
D-A-N-G-E-R. Shortcut.
I'll prove it to you.
Look at me. I'm closer to the station
because I'm taking the shortcut.
Let's go around. This way.
BING BONG: Almost there!
If you want to walk
the long way, go for it.
But Riley needs to be happy.
I'm not missing that train.
Bing Bong knows what he's doing.
JOY: He's part dolphin.
They're very smart.
SADNESS: Well, I guess.
- GIRL #1: What did you get?
- GIRL #2: I don't know.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Okay, what abstract concept
are we trying to comprehend today?
Um... Loneliness.
Hmm. Looks like
there's something in there.
I'm going to turn it on for a minute
and burn out the gunk.
BING BONG: What did I tell you?
You'll be at Headquarters in no time.
SADNESS: Whoa!
BING BONG: Say, would you look at that?
Whoa! What's happening?
Oh, no, they turned it on.
Huh. Never seen this before.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
My face! My beautiful face! Oh!
- What is going on?
- We're abstracting!
There are four stages.
This is the first:
Non-objective Fragmentation!
All right. Do not panic.
What is important is that
we all stay together. Oh!
(JOY EXCLAIMS)
We're in the second stage.
We're deconstructing!
Run! Ah!
I can't feel my legs!
Oh, there they are.
Come here, me!
(SADNESS GRUNTING)
We've got to get out of here
(YELLS IN PAIN)
before we're nothing
but shape and color!
Ow! We'll get stuck here forever!
Stuck? Why did we come in here?
I told you, it's a shortcut!
- (TRAIN HONKING HORN)
- (GASPS) The train!
(ALL GRUNTING)
SADNESS: Oh, no. We're
two-dimensional! That's stage three!
We're getting nowhere!
- Depth! I'm lacking depth!
- Come on.
(JOY GRUNTING)
We can't fit.
SADNESS: Oh, no, we're Nonfigurative.
This is the last stage!
BING BONG: We're not going to make it!
(SADNESS GROANING)
SADNESS: Wait! We're
two-dimensional. Fall on your face!
(BELL RINGING)
(JOY GRUNTING)
JOY: Stop! Stop!
Oh, no! I thought you said
that was a shortcut.
I did, but wow,
we should not have gone in there.
That was dangerous!
They really should put up a sign.
How long until the next train?
- Who knows. But don't worry.
- (GROANING)
There's another station. That way.
The train always stops there.
Right before it goes to Headquarters.
If we hurry, we can catch it.
This isn't another one
of your shortcuts, is it?
(LAUGHING) Yeah!
(WHISPERING) Is there
really another station?
Uh-huh. Through there.
BING BONG: Welcome to Imagination Land!
(GASPS) Imagination Land?
BING BONG: Sure!
I come here all the time.
I'm practically the mayor.
Hey, you guys hungry?
There's French Fry Forest!
- Mmm! Delicious.
- No way!
- (LAUGHING)
- (BING BONG EXCLAIMING)
BING BONG: Check it out! Trophy Town!
Medals! Ribbons! Everyone's a winner!
I won first place!
- Me too!
- Oh, participation award.
Wait, is that... Sadness,
look, it's Cloud Town!
(GASPS) That is my favorite!
(WHOOPING) Oh, it's so soft!
Oh! Let me try.
Hey! What's the big idea?
You better fix that wall,
or else you're in big troub...
(WHISTLING)
Oh, no! Lava! Whoo! Oh!
Imagination Land is the best!
Oh, is it all going
to be so interactive?
Hey, look! The House of Cards!
Oh, wait. Hang on just a minute.
- JOY: (GASPS) Your rocket!
- Yeah.
I stashed it in there for safekeeping,
and now I'm all set to
take Riley to the moon!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Great.
Oh, I love Imagination Land.
Isn't it great? And there's
always something new, like...
BING BONG: Who the heck is that?
Imaginary boyfriend.
I would die for Riley.
- (EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
- Oh, I've never seen him before.
I live in Canada.
Anyway, this way.
Through Preschool World!
We're nearly to the train!
Riley, here we come! Whoo-hoo!
(BING BONG LAUGHS)
This should be fun!
New team, new friends.
These kids look pretty good,
considering they're from San Francisco.
COACH: Okay, Andersen, you're up!
- Got to go.
- Okay.
Good luck, sweetie!
Luck isn't going to help us now.
If she tries to use Hockey Island,
it's going down.
Which is why I've recalled
every hockey memory I can think of.
One of these has got to work
- in place of the Core Memory.
- (WHISTLE BLOWING)
- She's about to play!
- Hurry!
(POWERING UP)
Ha-ha! We did it, gang! It's working!
Oh!
- (POWERING DOWN)
- (YELPS)
COACH: Line change! Line change!
- (GRUNTING)
- COACH: Change it up!
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHS) No! No! Aah!
(GRUNTS)
DISGUST: It's like
we don't learn anything.
- RILEY: Come on!
- COACH: Let's pick it up out there!
GIRL: Pass! Shoot it! Shoot it!
Oh!
(PANTING)
- That's it!
- No, no, no! Breathe.
Find your happy place. (CHOKES)
(YELLING)
- (RILEY GRUNTS)
- GIRL: What's her problem?
(RILEY GRUNTING)
- Riley. What's wrong?
- Let's go.
MOM: You're not going to finish tryouts?
- What's the point?
- Hey.
It'll be all right.
Let's just go back...
Stop saying everything
will be all right!
(GIRLS CHEERING)
COACH: Nice hustle, ladies!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(RUMBLING)
Hockey?
Oh, no, no, she loves hockey.
She can't give up hockey.
DAD: Hey! Look at that!
- Very nice shot!
- MOM: Hey!
Bing Bong, we have to
get to that station.
Sure thing. This way,
just past Graham Cracker Castle. Hey.
That's weird.
Graham Cracker Castle
used to be right here.
BING BONG: I wonder why
they moved it? Wow, that's not...
I would have sworn
Sparkle Pony Mountain was right here.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Yeah, yeah... I don't know...
- We'll have to come back.
- (GASPS) Princess Dream World!
Oh, no! The stuffed
Animal Hall of Fame!
(GASPS) My rocket!
BING BONG: Wait! Riley and I,
we're still using that rocket!
It still has some song power left!
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
(DISTORTED TUNE PLAYING)
No! No, no, no. No, you can't
take my rocket to the dump!
Riley and I are going to the moon!
Oh!
(BING BONG WHIMPERING)
Riley can't be done with me.
Hey, it's going to be okay!
We can fix this!
We just need to
get back to Headquarters.
Which way to the train station?
I had a whole trip planned for us.
(GASPS) Hey, who's ticklish, huh?
Here comes the tickle monster!
Hey, Bing Bong! Look at this!
(MAKING FUNNY SOUNDS)
Oh! Here's a fun game!
You point to the train station
and we all go there!
Won't that be fun? Come on,
let's go to the train station!
I'm sorry they took your rocket.
They took something that you loved.
It's gone. Forever.
Sadness. Don't make him feel worse.
Sorry.
It's all I had left of Riley.
I bet you and Riley
had great adventures.
Oh, they were wonderful.
Once we flew back in time.
We had breakfast twice that day.
Sadness...
It sounds amazing. I bet Riley liked it.
(SNIFFLING) Oh, she did.
We were best friends.
Yeah. It's sad.
(CRYING)
Wh...
(GROANS)
I'm okay now.
Come on. The train station is this way.
How did you do that?
Oh, I don't know. He was sad.
So I listened to what...
Hey! There's the train!
(TRAIN HONKING HORN)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Oh! We made it!
We're finally going to get home!
Oh, no! These Facts and Opinions
look so similar.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Happens all the time.
(GRUNTS)
On a scale of one to ten,
I give this day an F.
Well, why don't we quit standing
around and do something?
Like what, genius?
Like quitting. That's what I'm doing.
Sure it's the coward's way out.
But this coward's gonna survive.
Ow!
(EXCLAIMING)
DISGUST: Emotions can't quit, genius!
Ugh! I thought we were supposed to
be keeping Riley happy.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Mmm.
Aha! (LAUGHING)
- What is it?
- Oh, nothing.
- Just the best idea ever.
- What?
All the good Core Memories
were made in Minnesota.
Ergo, we go back to Minnesota
and make more.
- Ta-da!
- FEAR: Wait, wait, wait.
You're saying we run away?
Well, I wouldn't call it that.
I'd call it the Happy Core
Memory Development program.
You can't be serious.
Hey! Our life was perfect
until Mom and Dad decided to move to
San Fran Stinktown.
(STAMMERING) I mean,
it's just so drastic!
Need I remind you
of how great things were there?
Our room? Our back yard?
Our friends?
- MAN: ♪ TripleDent gum ♪
- WOMAN: ♪ Will make you smile ♪
- Did I ask for the gum commercial?
- (SONG STOPS PLAYING)
Anyway, it was better, that's my point.
Yeah, Riley was happier in Minnesota.
Wait. Hold on. Shouldn't we
just sleep on this or something?
Fine. (CHUCKLES) Let's sleep on it.
Because, hey,
I'm sure jolly fun-filled times
are just around the corner.
Huh?
Hey, hey! Why aren't we moving?
Riley's gone to sleep.
We're all on break.
You mean we're
stuck here until morning?
Yeah, the Train of Thought
doesn't run while she's asleep.
Oh, we can't wait that long.
- How about we wake her up?
- Sadness, that's ridiculous!
How could we possibly... (GASPS)
JOY: How about we wake her up?
- Great idea, Joy.
- Thanks. Come on!
Whoa! This place is huge!
Yeah, it looks so much smaller
than I expected.
Wow! I Can Fly?
BING BONG: I love that one!
(GASPS) Rainbow Unicorn!
She's right there!
My friend says you're famous.
She wants your autograph.
No, no, Sadness,
don't bother Miss Unicorn, okay?
Sorry, she's from out of town.
That was so embarrassing, right?
I loved you in
Fairy Dream Adventure Part 7.
Okay, bye. I love you!
Huh. Wonder what that means.
Oh, well, let's go in.
DIRECTOR: Set up the classroom set!
DIRECTOR: Today's memories are in!
DIRECTOR: We've got
a lot to work with here.
Riley dumped her best friend,
had a miserable day at school,
and quit hockey.
DIRECTOR: The writers have
put together a killer script!
Just because Joy and Sadness are gone,
I have to do stupid Dream Duty.
(GRUMBLING)
Okay. How are we going to wake her up?
Well, she wakes up sometimes
when she has a scary dream.
- We could scare her.
- Scare her?
No, she's been through enough already.
- But, Joy...
- Sadness, you may know your way
around down here, but I know Riley.
We're gonna make her so happy,
she'll wake up with exhilaration.
We'll excite her awake!
That's never happened before.
(GASPS) Ooh!
Riley loves dogs. Put this on.
I don't think that'll work.
- Bing Bong?
- BING BONG: Yeah?
Don't let anything happen to these.
Got it.
Mmm-hmm. Add the reality
distortion filter.
Love it. Remember,
play to the camera, everyone!
Riley is the camera!
DIRECTOR: Makeup, get out of there,
we are on in five,
four, three...
(STRUMMING DREAMY MUSIC)
Hello, class.
Before we begin today's pop quiz...
Man, she is one bad actress.
...which counts for 90%
of your final grade,
I want to introduce
our new student. Riley.
Would you like to stand up
- and introduce yourself?
- Camera.
- And cue Riley.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
(IN RILEY'S VOICE)
My name is Riley Andersen.
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
Ew, look! Her teeth are falling out!
- That's disgusting.
- Ew, gross!
Teeth falling out. (SPITS)
Yeah, I'm used to that one.
(SLURPS)
Let me guess, we have no pants on.
Hey, look! She came
to school with no pants on!
- FEAR: Called it!
- Ready?
I don't think
this happy thing is going to work.
But if we scare her...
Just follow my lead. Here we go.
(SCREAMING)
Bark! Bark! Bark!
- Who is that?
- Uh, what's going on?
Psst! You're on! Go!
Whoo! Let's party!
Let's dance! Whoo!
Hey, a party.
Bark, bark, bark!
- Joy, this isn't working.
- (FABRIC RIPS)
BING BONG: Huh!
- (CRASHING)
- (FABRIC RIPS)
Huh? Sadness, what are you doing?
- Come back here!
- (DOG BARKING)
It's just a dream,
it's just a dream. It's just a dream.
They're trying to wake her up.
Call security!
Hi, Riley, it's me!
- BING BONG: ♪ Who's your friend ♪
- Bing Bong?
♪ Who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong! ♪
JOY: Sadness, stop!
It was working!
BING BONG: Ow.
Sadness! You are ruining this dream!
You're scaring her!
But look, it's working!
Whoa.
They are not part
of this dream. Get them!
- SECURITY: Stop right there!
- BING BONG: Ow!
Pan away! Pan away!
(NEIGHS)
Boo! Pick a plotline!
- Ow! Careful!
- GUARD: Hold still!
BING BONG: You can't do this!
BING BONG: I know people
in Headquarters!
BING BONG: Ow! Cut that out!
Ow! Please!
Do you like candy? You look hungry.
I get you candy! Oh no!
JOY: No, no. No, no!
There go the Core Memories!
BING BONG: I can't go in there!
I'm scared of the dark!
Please!
Oh, come on.
JOY: What is this place?
SADNESS: The Subconscious.
It's where they take
all the troublemakers.
My hat feels loose.
Mmm. How do we get in?
GUARD #1: Let me see.
GUARD #2: You got my hat?
Or is that your hat?
GUARD #1: Yeah, it's my hat.
GUARD #2: You sure? I don't know,
look in the label.
- Yeah, it says, "My hat."
- Wait, it says, "My hat"?
- My hat, it says.
- That's what I wrote in my hat.
- What are you talking about?
- You've got my hat on.
- Okay, but it's my handwriting.
- (THUDDING)
- Hey! You!
- Oh! You caught us!
GUARD #1: Get back in there!
GUARD #1: No escaping!
(HOWLING)
(SADNESS WHIMPERING)
I don't like it here.
It's where they keep
Riley's darkest fears.
(GASPS)
It's broccoli.
- (DOOR CREAKING)
- (BOTH GASP)
SADNESS: The stairs to the basement!
(BOTH YELP)
(WHIRRING)
JOY: Grandma's vacuum cleaner!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Okay, come on.
(FOOTSTEPS CRUNCHING)
Would you walk quieter?
I'm trying.
What is going...
Candy wrappers? (GASPS)
(BING BONG CRYING)
- JOY: Bing Bong!
- Joy?
- There you are.
- Shhh!
- (SNORING)
- (BOTH GASP)
It's Jangles.
Who's the birthday girl?
Do you have the Core Memories?
Yeah.
All he cared about was the candy!
Shh.
(SQUEAKING)
(JOY GRUNTING)
(CONTINUES SNORING)
We're out of here!
Let's get to that train!
Wait! The train's not running.
We still have to wake up Riley.
But how?
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Oh, no!
(SQUEAKS)
(JANGLES GROANS)
Hey, Sadness.
(STAMMERING) Did you hear
about the pa-pa-party they were having?
Oh, yeah. Oh, yes, Joy.
(STUTTERING)
Isn't it a birthday party?
Did you say
birthday? (LAUGHS)
And there's going to be
cake and presents.
And games and balloons...
A birthday?
Okay. Follow us!
(JANGLES LAUGHING)
Nothing like a good scare
to wake you up, right?
Okay, but it's my handwriting.
No it isn't. That's my... I wrote that.
No, but this one's my handwriting.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(JANGLES LAUGHING)
(SILLY MUSIC PLAYING)
(CRASHING)
Who's the birthday girl?
(SHRIEKS)
(GASPING)
(BELL DINGS)
- Whoo-hoo!
- Come on, let's go!
(TRAIN HONKING HORN)
JOY: Ha-ha! We made it!
Guess who's on their way
to Headquarters!
SADNESS: We are!
- BING BONG: Whoo-hoo!
- JOY: Whoo!
(ALL WHOOPING)
- What is going on?
- He did it again!
We were at school, and we were
naked, and there was a dog,
and his back half was chasing him
and then we saw Bing Bong!
You idiot! It was a dream!
This is ridiculous!
We can't even get
a good night's sleep anymore.
Time to take action.
Stupid Mom and Dad.
If they hadn't moved us,
none of this would've happened.
Who's with me?
(STUTTERING) Um...
No no no no no.
(SIGHS) Yeah. Let's do it.
She took it. There's no turning back.
So how are we going
to get to Minnesota from here?
Well, why don't we go down
to the elephant lot
and rent an elephant?
Hey. That sounds nice.
We're taking the bus, nitwit!
ANGER: There's a bus
leaving tomorrow. Perfect!
A ticket costs money.
How do we get money?
- Mom's purse.
- (GASPS) You wouldn't.
Oh, but I would.
Where was it we saw it last?
- ♪ TripleDent gum ♪
- No!
- (FEAR SCREAMS)
- It's downstairs somewhere.
Mom and Dad got us into this mess.
ANGER: They can pay to get us out.
How about this, huh? Isn't this nice?
You can see everything from up here.
Look, there's Inductive Reasoning.
There's Déja Vu.
There's Language Processing.
There's Critical Thinking.
There's Déja Vu.
Hey, look at this, guys! Memories!
Hey. That was a good idea.
About scaring Riley awake.
JOY: You're not so bad.
Really?
Nice work.
JOY: Oh, I can't wait
to get the old Riley back.
As soon as we get there,
I'm going to fix this whole mess.
Whoa. Is this Riley?
She's so big now.
She won't fit in my rocket.
How are we gonna get to the moon?
Oh, it's that time
in the twisty tree, remember?
The hockey team showed up
and Mom and Dad were there cheering.
JOY: Look at her,
having fun and laughing.
Oh, I love this one.
Hmm. I love that one, too.
Atta girl! Now you're getting it!
Yeah. It was the day the Prairie Dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful. She wanted to quit.
Sorry. I went sad again, didn't I?
I'll tell you what. We can keep working
on that when we get back. Okay?
Okay.
MOM: But I just don't understand.
Why did our moving van
even go to Texas?
Multiple customers?
Well, we were promised
delivery on the fifth.
Uh-huh.
Excuse me, isn't there
any way that you can rush it?
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
JOY: Honesty Island?
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GASPS) Look out!
ENGINEER: Come on!
- (ALL SCREAMING)
- Hold on!
Hurry up! Come on! Over here!
WORKER: Come on, people!
Let's, go, go, go!
JOY: That was our way home.
We lost another island?
What is happening?
Haven't you heard?
Riley's running away.
What?
FEAR: Wait, wait, hang on, guys.
Are we really doing this?
- I mean, this is serious.
- Look.
We have no Core Memories.
ANGER: You want Riley to be happy?
Let's get back to
Minnesota and make more.
Joy, if we hurry,
we can still stop her.
Family Island. Let's go!
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS) Joy! Joy!
SADNESS: It's too dangerous!
- SADNESS: We won't make it in time.
- (THUDDING)
But that's our only way back!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
A recall tube!
We can get recalled!
MOM: Have a great day, sweetheart.
See you after school, monkey.
(IMITATING MONKEY GRUNTING)
We love you!
Go! Run, run! Go!
Whoa! Whoa!
Sadness! Sadness, stop!
You're hurting Riley!
Oh, no, no, no! I did it again!
If you get in here,
these Core Memories will get sad.
(RUMBLING)
I'm sorry.
Riley needs to be happy.
Joy?
(GASPS)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
Joy! (SCREAMING)
Joy!
(JOY GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Joy?
(GASPS)
Joy!
(GRUNTING)
Joy, what are you doing?
Will you stop it, please?
(JOY PANTING)
Don't you get it, Joy?
We're stuck down here.
We're forgotten.
RILEY: We used to play tag and stuff.
But everything's different now.
Since we moved.
(RILEY SNIFFLING)
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFLES)
(RILEY LAUGHING)
(RILEY TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(JOY SNIFFLING)
(RILEY HUMMING)
Do you remember how she used to
stick her tongue out
when she was coloring?
I could listen to her stories all day.
(RILEY LAUGHING)
I just wanted Riley to be happy.
And now...
(CRYING)
(RILEY LAUGHING)
(KIDS CHEERING)
SADNESS: It was the day
the Prairie Dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful.
She wanted to quit.
(ALL CHEERING)
Sadness.
Mom and Dad... The team...
They came to help because of Sadness.
We have to get back up there.
Joy, we're stuck down here.
We might as well be on another planet.
Another planet.
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" ♪
♪ Who's the best in every way ♪
♪ And wants to sing this song to say? ♪
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" ♪
(JOY GRUNTING)
Hop in.
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" ♪
♪ Who's the best in every way ♪
♪ And wants to sing this song to say ♪
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ Who's the best in every way ♪
♪ And wants to sing the song to say... ♪
(JOY SCREAMING)
Come on!
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ Who's the best in every way
And wants to sing this song to say ♪
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play? ♪
- (JOY GRUNTS)
- BING BONG: Ow!
(GROANS)
BING BONG: Come on, Joy. One more time.
I got a feeling about this one.
♪ Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ Who's the best in every way
And wants to sing this song to say ♪
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
- Louder! Joy, sing louder!
- (JOY SINGING)
♪ To sing this song to say ♪
- ♪ Who's your friend who likes to... ♪
- (SCREAMS)
♪ Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong ♪
♪ His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
♪ Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say ♪
♪ Bing Bong ♪
We're gonna make it!
Whoo-hoo! Bing Bong! We did it!
We... Bing Bong? Bing Bong!
(BING BONG WHOOPING)
BING BONG: You made it!
(BING BONG LAUGHING)
Go! Go save Riley!
Take her to the moon for me. Okay?
(WHIMPERS)
I'll try, Bing Bong.
I promise.
We're home!
Riley? Riley!
I'll call her cell.
Oh, this is terrible.
Wait, is that someone
walking towards us?
Yep, let's cross the street.
(PHONE RINGING)
(GASPS) It's Mom.
She's onto us!
- What do we do?
- Where's my bag?
Riley needs to get Core Memories.
- FEAR: That's the stuff.
- We keep going.
(RUMBLING)
Sadness!
Sadness! Sadness?
Come on, Sadness.
Where are you? Okay.
If I were Sadness, where would I be?
Oh. Everything is awful
and my legs don't work,
and you have to drag me around
while I touch all the...
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh, no! It's Mom again! What do we do?
(ANGER GRUNTS)
(RINGING STOPS)
This is madness!
She shouldn't run away!
Let's get this idea
out of her head. (STRAINING)
Sadness?
(GASPS) Sadness!
Joy?
Wait! Sadness!
Just let me go!
Riley's better off without me!
JOY: Come back!
Okay, you're saying your husband
was blown away by an elephant.
Was he with anyone?
Yes! And there she is!
Hey! Come back here!
Forget it, Jake. It's Cloud Town.
Oh! What? Sadness!
(SOBBING) I only
make everything worse!
Wait! Sadness!
We got to get you back to...
(RUMBLING)
- It's stuck!
- Oh, great.
- What do you mean it's stuck?
- Now what?
Oh, no no no no! What is this?
(GRUNTS)
- How do we stop it?
- I got it!
Make her feel scared!
That'll make her change her mind!
- Brilliant!
- DISGUST: I know it's brilliant! Do it!
Ah! Nothing's working!
Why isn't it working?
- Let me try.
- Great! You broke it!
- No, I didn't! Don't touch that!
- (ARGUING)
- Let me do it! Get out of here!
- (ALL GRUNTING)
Guys, we can't make Riley feel anything.
What have we done?
Hey! Hey, look at me!
Did you mean what you said before?
I would die for Riley!
Yeah, okay, haircut. Time to prove it.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
I would die for Riley!
(WAILING)
That's it! I fold!
Whoa!
Whoa.
IMAGINARY BOYFRIENDS: Whoa!
This is crazy. This is crazy.
No, no, no. Joy. Be positive.
I am positive this is crazy!
- Now!
- IMAGINARY BOYFRIENDS: For Riley!
- Joy?
- Hang on!
Oh, I wish Joy was here!
It's Joy!
ANGER: Stand back!
That worked.
Well, what would you do,
if you're so smart?
I'd tell you, but you're
too dumb to understand.
- What?
- Of course your tiny brain is confused.
Guess I'll just have to
dumb it down to your level.
Sorry I don't speak moron
as well as you,
but let me try. Duh!
(SCREAMS)
FEAR: Oh, thank goodness you're back!
- Things are really messed up!
- We found this idea.
We were just trying to
make happy memories.
Joy, you got to fix this! Get up there!
Sadness, it's up to you.
- Me?
- ALL: Sadness?
I can't, Joy.
Yes, you can. Riley needs you.
Okay.
Wait! Stop! I want to get off!
(BRAKES SCREECH)
All right. Thank you. We will.
Her teacher hasn't even
seen Riley all day.
- What?
- What was she wearing last?
- Do you even remember what...
- I can't believe this.
DAD: Riley, there you are!
Thank goodness!
MOM: We were worried sick!
Where have you been? It's so late!
DAD: Oh, honey!
What happened? Are you all right?
MOM: We asked the neighbors,
I called the school,
we talked to your teacher.
(GIGGLING)
(SNIFFLING)
I know you don't want me to but...
I miss home.
I miss Minnesota.
You need me to be happy, but...
I want my old friends,
and my hockey team.
I want to go home.
Please don't be mad.
Oh, sweetie.
We're not mad.
You know what? I miss Minnesota too.
I miss the woods where we took hikes.
And the backyard where you used to play.
Spring Lake, where you learned to skate.
Come here.
(SOBBING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
FEAR: Hey, I'm liking this new view.
ANGER: Friendship Island has expanded.
Glad they finally opened
that Friendly Argument section.
I like Tragic Vampire Romance Island.
Fashion Island?
Oh. Everyone shut up.
Boy Band Island?
Hope that's just a phase.
Say what you want,
I think it's all beautiful.
(DRILL WHIRRING)
All right. Here you go.
Your new expanded console
is up and runnin'.
- Ooh!
- Wow!
- Cool! Upgrade!
- Ooh!
- Hey! Whoa-ho!
- (BEEPS)
Whoops, wait. Did I just do that?
Hey, guys? What's pub-er-ty?
I don't know.
It's probably not important.
Whoa. I have access to
the entire curse word library!
This new console is the...
(BEEPS)
Sorry. I did it again. My bad.
They're getting to the rink.
DAD: Now when you get out there,
you be aggressive!
- I know, Dad.
- MOM: But not too aggressive.
You know, you guys don't
have to come to every game.
Are you kidding? I'm not missing one!
Go Foghorns!
Go Riley! Foghorns are the best!
- (DAD BELLOWING)
- Okay! I got to go!
- Aw!
- They love us.
Yeah, Mom and Dad are pretty cool.
Guys, of course they are.
But we can't show it.
(ALL CHEERING)
She loved the face painting!
Ha! Told you it was a great idea!
Best idea he's had in a while.
He's a really good guy.
(ALL SIGHS)
Just in case.
Oh!
Sorry.
(ALL SCREAMING)
ALARM: Girl! Girl! Girl!
Uh... Okay. Bye.
COACH: Remember, just hustle.
GIRL #1: Go, Riley!
GIRL #2: You got this!
- You ready?
- Yeah.
All right. Let's play some hockey!
- (WHISTLE BLOWING)
- JOY: All right, Anger, take it!
ANGER: Give us that puck
or you're dead meat!
FEAR: On our left. On our left!
DISGUST: Let's just try not
to get all smelly this time.
SADNESS: Oh. Mom and Dad
are watching us fail.
ANGER: Not for long!
JOY: We've been through
a lot lately, that's for sure.
But we still love our girl.
She has great new friends,
a great new house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all, Riley's twelve now.
What could happen?
And who can tell me what year
San Francisco was founded?
Anyone? Jordan?
JORDAN: Uh...
How much more of this?
Five months, two weeks and four days
until summer vacation.
Then it's off to the Bahamas
with you know who!
Come fly with me, gatinha.
(ALL SIGHS)
(CASH REGISTER RINGING)
Have a nice day.
What are we mad about?
I don't know.
Whatever Troy's mad about.
What's Troy mad about?
I don't know.
I know. Totally.
We're a total fraud!
Do you think
they can see through us?
Of course not!
We're wearing eye shadow!
Being cool is so exhausting.
Who's the birthday girl?
Huh? Hey! Hello?
Six years of drama school for this?
WOMAN: Move it, will you?
(HORNS HONKING)
(GIRL BABBLING NOISILY)
ALL: What are you doing? Come on!
You know what?
This is okay. This is fine.
We just need to go
to our happy place.
♪ TripleDent gum ♪
- No! Not this again!
- (ALL EXCLAIMING)
(SNIFFING)
(DOG BARKING)
(MEOWING)
(HISSING)
(BEEPING)
(SCREECHING)
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: October 20, 2015